&gt;&gt; Good afternoon everyone,
&gt;&gt;大家下午好
welcome to our talk on using
欢迎参加“Metal 2
Metal 2 for Compute.
的计算功能”会议
My name is Anna Tikhonova.
我叫 Anna Tikhonova
I'm an engineer on the GPU
是 GPU 软件团队的
Software Team, so let's begin.
工程师 现在就开始吧
The Metal 2 echo system is so
Metal 2 回波系统的功能
much more than the Metal API and
比 Metal API 和语言要
the language.
多得多
We also have the GPU Tools and
我们还拥有 GPU 工具
we have the MetalKit and Metal
以及 MetalKit 和
Performance Shaders frameworks.
Metal Performance Shader 框架
You might know Metal as this
你可能会认为 Metal 是
great technology for developing
开发高端游戏和图像
high-end games and graphics.
的优秀技术
But it can also be used for
但它同时也用于
Compute processing.
计算处理
In fact, the Compute side of
事实上 Metal 在计算方面
Metal is so powerful and
非常强大和灵活
flexible that the Metal
以至于 Metal
Performance Shaders framework is
Performance Shader 框架
built completely on top of
完全建立在
Compute.
计算之上
And in this session, we'll talk
在本次会议中 我们将介绍
about what's new in the Metal
Metal Performance Shader 框架
Performance Shaders framework.
的新功能
We introduced the Metal
我们在 2015 年推出了
Performers Shaders framework, or
Metal Performers Shader 框架
MPS in 2015.
简称 MPS
And the videos of our past
之前的会议视频
sessions are available on our
可以在我们的开发者
developer website.
网站上找到
MPS uses the compute power of
MPS 利用 GPU 的
the GPU to bring GPU accelerated
计算功能为 GPU 提供
primitives.
加速图元
For image processing, linear
用于图像处理
algebra and machine learning.
线性代数和机器学习
The framework is optimized for
这个框架针对 iOS
iOS and we're happy to announce
进行了优化 我们很高兴地宣布
that this year we're also
今年 MPS 也将在
bringing MPS to the Mac.
Mac 上应用
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thank you.
谢谢
The entire feature set is
整个功能集都
available in both iOS and macOS.
可以在 iOS 和 macOS 系统中使用
So let's begin with a quick
所以我们先来快速地
update on our image processing
看一下图像处理支持的
support.
新进展
So here's a list of all of the
这里列出了
primitives for image processing
在 iOS 10 中可以使用的
that we had available in iOS 10.
所有图像处理图元
So there's Convolution, Gaussian
有 Convolution Gaussian Blur
Blur, Lanczos Resampling, just
Lanczos Resampling
to name a few.
就举几个例子
They're all now available in
这些现在都可以在 macOS 系统中
macOS.
使用了
And this year we're bringing you
今年我们为大家带来
four new image processing
四种新的图像处理
primitives.
图元
The Image Keypoints primitive
Image Keypoint
can be used -- is often used in
图元可以用于 通常用于
computer vision algorithms such
计算机视觉算法 例如
as image stabilization and
稳像和
Bilinear Rescale, Image
双线性缩放
Statistics, and Element-wise
图像统计
Arithmetic Operators, are
元素级算术运算符
commonly used to pre-process
通常用于图像
images.
预处理
For example, in machine
例如在机器
learning.
学习中
And the arithmetic filters also
算术递增滤色镜也
support broadcasting operations.
支持广播操作
Which, for example, allow you to
例如 允许
add a 2D image or the 1D image.
添加 2D 图像或 1D 图像
So that's it for our very quick
这就是我们对图像处理
update on image processing.
新进展的快速介绍
And now let's talk about the new
现在我们来谈谈新的
Linear Algebra operations.
线性代数运算
Without support, Matrix
没有矩阵乘法
Multiplication, Matrix Vector
矩阵向量
Multiplication, and Triangular
乘法 三角
Matrix Factorization and Linear
矩阵因式分解和
Solvers.
线性求解器的支持
To support Linear Algebra
为了支持线性代数
operations, we now have multiple
运算 我们现在有了很多
new data representations.
新的数据表示
First, we have the MPSVector
首先是 MPSVector 对象
object which interprets the data
它可以将 Metal
in a metal buffer as a
缓冲区中的数据解释为
one-dimensional array.
一维数组
And we have an MPSMatrix object
然后是 MPSMatrix 对象
which interprets the data in a
它可以将 Metal 缓冲区中的
metal buffer as a rectangular
数据解释为矩形
array.
数组
And MPS matrices are in role
而 MPS 矩阵以行序为
major order.
主序
And you can think of both
你可以将
MPSVectors and MPSMatrices as
MPSVector 和 MPSMatrice 都看作是
wrappers around user data
用户数据缓冲区周围的
buffers.
封装
And we also support a temporary
而且我们也支持 MPSMatrix 的
variance of MPSMatrix.
临时变化
MPS images -- temporary images
MPS 图像 临时图像
and MPSTemporaryMatrices are
和 MPS 临时矩阵从
allocated from a Metal heap
与命令缓冲区相关联的
associated with a command
Metal 堆中分配
buffer.
出来
And they are called temporary
之所以称为临时的
because their lifespan is
是因为它们的寿命
limited to the lifetime of the
受限于命令缓冲区的
command buffer.
使用寿命
And we recommend you use
我们建议
temporary images and matrices
在大多数中间存储器中
for most of your intermediate
使用临时映像和
storage.
矩阵
Both MPSVector and MPSMatrix
MPSVector 和 MPSMatrix 都
support a number of input types.
支持多种输入类型
We support single-precision and
我们支持单精度
half-precision input types and a
半精度输入类型以及
floating-point input types.
浮点输入类型
And 16-bits and 8-bit signed
还有 16 位和 8 位带符号
integer input types.
整数输入类型
And now let's take a look at how
现在我们来看看怎样
we can create an MPSVector of
创建大小为 N 的
size N.
MPS 向量
So if you don't already have a
如果你还没有
Metal buffer, you need to create
Metal 缓冲区 那就需要先
one.
创建一个
And then you need to create a
然后再为你的向量
descriptor for your vector.
创建一个描述符
And note here that you specify
请注意 你需要指定
the length of the vector.
向量的长度
That's because the vector can be
因为向量可以
made from a portion of the
由原来 Metal 缓冲区的
original Metal buffer.
一部分形成
And other related offsets can be
并且可以在使用该向量
set in a kernel that will use
的内核中设置其他相关的
this vector.
偏移量
And then the last step is
最后使用
creating a vector from the
描述符从缓冲区
buffer with a descriptor.
创建一个向量
And now let's take a look at how
现在我们来看看
you can create an MPSMatrix with
如何创建一个 M 行
M rows and N columns.
N 列的 MPS 矩阵
So it's very similar to the way
这和创建 MPS 向量
you would create MPSVector, but
的方式非常类似
there's just a few things we
但有几点
want to mention.
需要注意
We provide a convenient API that
我们提供了一个方便的 API
you can use to find the
你可以用它来查找
recommended bytes per row value
每个行值的推荐字节数
for sizing your Metal buffers.
用于调整 Metal 缓冲区的大小
And if you choose to use the
如果你选择使用 API
API, this is how you would
那么这就是
create a metal buffer with this
使用这个推荐值创建 Metal 缓冲区
recommended value.
的方法
And using this API is completely
并且这个 API 是完全
optional, but recommended for
可以选择性使用的 但我们推荐使用
better performance.
因为它的性能更好
And then the rest is simple.
其余的就简单了
You create a descriptor for your
你先为矩阵创建一个
matrix, and then you create a
描述符 然后创建一个
matrix with a descriptor.
带有描述符的矩阵
And now that we talked about the
既然刚刚我们讲过了
data presentations, now let's
数据表示 那么现在
talk about the primitives.
我们来看一下图元
So for Matrix-Matrix and
对于矩阵-矩阵和
Matrix-Vector multiplication our
矩阵-向量的乘法 我们的
API is modeled after the
API 以
standard BLAS GEMM and GEMV
标准的 BLAS GEMM 和 GEMV
interfaces.
界面为模型
And for triangular matrix
对于三角矩阵
vectorization and linear
矢量化和线性
solvers, our API is modeled
求解器 我们的 API 以
after standard LAPACK
标准的 LAPACK
decomposition and solve
分解和求解
interfaces.
界面为模型
So if you're familiar with those
所以如果你熟悉这些
interfaces our API will look
界面 那对我们的 API
very familiar to you as well.
你也不会陌生
And now let's take a look at a
现在我们来看一个
very simple code example.
非常简单的代码示例
So we'll be doing matrix
我们要做矩阵的
multiplication and computing
乘法和计算
just C = A times B.
C = A 乘以 B
So first we need to create our
所以首先我们需要创建
matrices A, B and C.
矩阵 A B 和 C
But I know you know how to do
但我知道大家已经知道怎么
this, I showed you in a previous
操作了 因为在前一张幻灯片里我已经
slide, so let's move on.
讲过 所以我们继续往下看
Now we want to run matrix
现在我们要在 GPU 上
multiplication on the GPU.
运行矩阵的乘法
So first we do our usual Metal
首先像往常一样进行 Metal
setup to getting a device, a
设置来获取设备
command queue, and a command
命令队列和命令
buffer.
缓冲区
And then we need to create our
然后我们需要创建
matrix multiplication kernel.
矩阵乘法内核
And note here that you specify
注意 你这里需要
the size of the result.
指定结果的大小
That's because this kernel can
因为这个内核可以
operate on subregions of
在矩阵的子区域上
matrices.
运行
And then we encode this kernel
然后将这个内核编码
to the GPU and tell it to start
到 GPU 上 并让它开始
doing the work.
工作
And we already have sample code
我们已经在
from Matrix multiplication
开发者网站上提供了
available on our developer
矩阵乘法的示例代码
website, and the sample code for
以及三角矩阵
triangular matrix vectorization
向量化的代码
and solving a system of linear
求解线性方程组的示例代码
equations is coming very soon.
很快也要发布
So that's it for our -- for the
这就是我们关于
linear algebra operations.
线性代数运算的内容
Let's now move on to the next
现在我们来看下一个
topic, which is Accelerating
主题 也就是
Machine Learning Primitives on
在 GPU 上加速机器
the GPU.
学习图元
There are a number of
在今年的 WWDC
machine-learning related talks
大会上有很多关于
at WWDC this year.
机器学习的会议
And we are a part of the
而我们就是机器学习
machine-learning community.
团体的一部分
And this slide shows the overall
这一页展示了
architecture.
整体的架构
So as an application developer,
作为一名应用程序开发人员
you can add machine learning
你可以通过使用
functionality to your
高级域
applications by using high-level
特定框架
domain-specific frameworks such
比如分区框架
as division framework and the
和依赖于 Core ML 框架的
natural language processing
自然语言处理框架
framework, which rely on the
为应用程序添加
Core ML framework.
机器学习功能
And the Core ML framework is
Core ML 框架由
powered by the accelerates
CPU 上的
framework BNNS primitives on the
加速框架 BNNS
CPU.
原语
And by the machine learning --
以及 GPU 上的
and by the Metal Performance
机器学习和
Shaders framework on the GPU.
MPS 框架驱动构成
But if you're writing an
但是如果你正在编写一个
application that uses Metal,
使用 Metal 的应用程序
then you can use the MPS
那么你可以直接使用
framework directly and I will
MPS框架 我稍后
show you how in this session.
将在这个会议中向你展示如何操作
So let's start with what are we
让我们从正在讲的
talking about here?
这个部分开始
What is deep learning?
什么是深度学习
What is Machine learning?
什么是机器学习
So imagine that this is you.
想象一下这是你
And when you see an image, you
当你看到一个图像
know immediately what's depicted
你立刻就能知道上面描绘的
on it.
是什么
It's a panda.
这是一只熊猫
But now think about all of the
现在想一想你的
images on your iPhone.
iPhone 上所有的图像
Or all of those pictures in your
或者你家庭相册中的
family albums.
所有照片
Or all of the images on the
或者互联网上的
internet.
所有图像
No human can possibly -- can
没有人可以
classify these many images.
将这么多的图像分类
But deep-learning algorithms is
但深度学习算法就是
designed specifically to do
专门为此而
that.
设计的
They can be used for sifting
它们可以用于筛选
through large amounts of data
大量数据
and answering questions such as
并回答诸如
what is in this image?
图像的内容是什么 等一系列问题
Deep learning algorithms have
深度学习算法有
two phases.
两个阶段
Training and inference.
训练和推理
So let's talk about training
让我们先来讲一下
first.
训练
And let's actually use an
让我们用一个
example.
例子
Let's train a system to classify
我们训练一个系统来进行
images.
图像分类
So the training system to
这个系统训练可以
classify images, for example, if
进行图像分类 例如
you want to have it recognize
你想让系统识别
animals.
动物
Like, to have it recognize cats,
要让它识别猫
you need to feed this system a
那么你就需要为这个系统输入
large number of labeled images
大量的包含
of cats and then rabbits, and
猫 兔子和
all the other animals that you
所有其他你希望
want your system to be able to
系统能识别动物的
recognize.
标签的图像
And this training step is a
而这个训练步骤是
one-time computationally
一次性的
expensive and labor-intensive
它消耗计算能力且劳动
step.
强度大
And it's usually done offline.
它通常是离线完成的
But the results of this training
但是训练阶段的结果
phase is trained parameters
是下一阶段
which are required for the next
也就是推理阶段
phase, the inference phase.
所需要的训练参数
This is when your system is
这时候可以将一个从未见过的
presented with a new image that
新图像呈现在
it has never seen before and it
你的系统中
needs to classify, this is a
并对其进行分类
cap.
这是一个帽子
We provide view acceleration for
我们为第二阶段
the second phase; the inference
也就是推理阶段提供视图
phase.
加速
Specifically, last year we
具体来说 去年我们
talked about the building blocks
讨论了在 GPU 上
for building convolutional
构建卷积神经网络的
neural networks on the GPU for
构建块 用于
inference.
推理
So before we move onto any of
所以在继续介绍
the new features for machine
今年推出的
learning that we brought you
机器学习的新功能
this year, we are going to
之前 我们将
review some of the core
回顾一下
information that was covered in
去年演讲中介绍的
our last year's presentation.
一些核心信息
Such as, what are convolutional
比如 什么是卷积
neural networks?
神经网络
And once we do that then we can
在这之后 我们才会
talk about the new primitives
谈到今年为
that we've added for
卷积神经网络添加的
convolutional neural networks
新原语
this year, and then we'll
然后我们将
introduce the new, easy-to-use
介绍一种新的 易用的
neural network graph API.
神经网络图像 API
And our last topic will be
而我们最后一个话题是
recurrent neural networks.
循环神经网络
So let's go into our recap.
让我们按照刚才的概述开始讲
So what are convolutional neural
那么 什么是卷积神经
networks?
网络
Convolutional neural networks
卷积神经网络
are biologically inspired and
受生物学启发而设计出来
designed to resemble the visual
用于近似
cortex.
视觉皮质
So let's think about how our
所以让我们想一下
brain processes visual inputs.
大脑是如何处理视觉输入的
The first hierarchy of neurons
在视觉皮质中
that receive information in the
接收信息的第一层
visual cortex is sensitive to
神经元对
specific edges and blobs of
特定的边缘和色块很
color.
敏感
While the brain region's further
而大脑区域进一步的
down the visual pipeline respond
视觉传递会对
to more complex structures such
更复杂的结构做出反应
as faces of our friends or kinds
比如朋友的面孔或者
of animals like cats.
动物 比如猫
So in a similar way, CNNs are
所以类似的 卷积神经网络
organized into a hierarchy of
是多层次结构
layers where high-level features
其中高级特征
are derived from low-level
源于低级
features.
特征
So the first few layers in your
因此你的网络中的前几个
network respond to low-level
层次会对低级特征
features like edges and blobs of
比如边缘和色块做出
color.
响应
While subsequent layers respond
而随后的层次
to progressively more complex
对逐渐复杂的特征
features such as faces.
比如面孔 做出响应
And I keep saying features.
我一直在说特征
So think of a feature as a
你可以将特征视为
filter that filters your input
一个过滤器 可以过滤输入的
data; that particular feature.
数据 就是那个特征
And here's a list of all of the
这里列出了我们在
CNN primitives that we had
iOS 10 中提供的
available in iOS 10.
所有卷积神经网络原语
And in this recap I will be just
在这个概述中我将
talking about the core
只讲核心
convolution layer.
卷积层
The core building block of a
CNN 的核心
CNN.
构建块
And the rest of these primitives
这些原语的其余部分
are covered in great detail in
在我们的演讲文档中
our presentation -- in our
有很详细的
documentation.
介绍
So Pooling, Fully-Connected and
Pooling Fully-Connected 和
SoftMax.
SoftMax.
You can find information on
你可以找到和这些相关的
those.
信息
So let's talk about the core
所以让我们来谈谈
building block.
核心构建块
So the function of this core
这个核心卷积层的功能
convolution layer is to
是识别输入
recognize features in the input
数据中的特征
data and it's called a
它之所以被称为
convolution layer because it
卷积层是因为
performs a convolution on its
它对输入进行
input.
卷积操作
So let's recall how regular
我们回想一下常规的
convolution works.
卷积如何进行
You have your inputs, your
你有输入
outputs and the filter.
输出和过滤器
And to convole a filter with the
使用输入数据来
input data you need to multiply
调用过滤器 你需要将
each value in your filter with
过滤器中的
the value in the input data and
每个值与输入数据中的值相乘
combine that information to
并将该信息组合
compute a single output value.
从而计算出单个输出值
And you do the same for the rest
对于其余的输出像素
of the output pixels.
你也进行同样的操作
And now the convolution layer is
而现在卷积层则是
a generalization of regular
常规卷积的
convolution.
一般化
It allows you to have multiple
它允许你拥有多个
filters.
过滤器
So you have as many filters as
所以你可以拥有和输出通道
you have output channels -- or
一样多的过滤器
16 in this case.
这种情况下是 16 个
And these are the filters which
这些过滤器将
are going to be filtering input
过滤具有特定
data for particular features.
特征的输入数据
Now imagine that you're working
现在想象一下你正在
with RGB data.
使用 RGB 数据
So you actually have three
那么你的输入实际上
channels in your input.
有三个通道
And just because how CNNs work,
鉴于 CNN 的工作原理
this means you need three sets
这意味着你需要三组过滤器
of 16 filters.
每组 16 个
One set for each input channel.
每个输入通道一组
And then these filters are
然后将这些滤波器
applied to the input data
分别应用于
separately.
输入数据
And then the final step combines
然后最后一步将
all of this information to
所有这些信息合并
compute a single output pixel.
计算出单个输出像素
So that's it for our recap of
这就是我们对
the convolution layer.
卷积层的概述
Now let's talk about the new
现在我们来谈谈
primitives we've added for
为卷积神经网络
convolutional neural networks.
添加的新原语
So as you can see, we've added
如你所见 我们添加了
quite a few.
不少原语
And I'll be talking about the
但我接下来只讲一下
ones highlighted in yellow, but
黄色的部分
the rest of them like L2Norm
其他的比如 L2Norm
Pooling, Resampling,
Pooling Resampling
Up-sampling, they will all be
和 Up-sampling 这些都将
covered in our documentation.
在我们的文档中介绍
So let's talk about updates to
那让我们来看看对核心
our core convolution layer.
卷积层进行的更新
We used to support only single
我们过去只支持
precision floating-point weight
单精度浮点权重
types.
类型
And now to help you reduce the
现在为了帮你减少
memory footprint and to prove
内存占用并
the performance of your
提高网络
networks.
性能
We also support half-precision
我们还支持半精度
floating points, 8-bit integer,
浮点 8 位整数
and binary weight types.
和二进制权重类型
We used to support only standard
我们过去只支持标准
convolution and now we also
卷积 现在
support binary and XNOR
我们也支持二进制和
convolution.
XNOR 卷积
Dilated convolution.
扩张卷积
Sub-pixel convolution and
子像素卷积和
convolution transpose
卷积转置
operations.
操作
And many of these are
其中许多是
orthogonal, so you can even have
正交的 所以如果你愿意的话
dilated sub-pixel convolution if
甚至可以进行
you want.
扩大子像素卷积
So let's go through them
让我们一个一个地
one-by-one.
看一下
Binary and XNOR convolution
二进制和 XNOR 卷积
perform the same exact operation
与常规卷积执行
as regular convolution but they
相同的精确操作 但它们具有
do so with improved performance
更好的性能 而且能够
and great space savings.
节省极大的空间
So in regular convolution, you
所以在常规卷积中
may have floating point inputs
你可能有浮点输入
and floating point weights.
和浮点权重
What binary convolution allow
而二进制卷积能够
you to do is to use your
允许你
full-sized input with binary
使用二进制权重的全尺寸
weights.
输入
And for XNOR convolution the
而对于 XNOR 卷积
first thing that happens is that
首先
your input is first converted to
你的输入会被转换为
binary so that both your inputs
二进制的 从而使输入
and the weights are binary.
和权重都是二进制的
In regular convolution, the
在常规卷积中
input has to be multiplied with
输入必须与权重
the weights.
相乘
And for XNOR convolution the
而对于 XNOR 卷积
separation becomes a simple XNOR
分离变成了一个简单的 XNOR
operation.
操作
And now let's talk about dilated
现在我们来谈谈扩张
convolution.
卷积
So we already know how regular
我们已经知道常规
convolution works.
卷积如何工作
You need to apply a filter to
你需要用过滤器对
the input data to compute a
输入数据进行计算
single output value.
来得到单个输出值
But say you're working on an
但如果你正在研究一种
algorithm that requires global
需要将更广泛的
integration of a wider context
输入数据进行
of your input data.
全局集成的算法
So instead of a 3 by 3 kernel,
那么你就不能用 3 乘 3 的内核
you may be using a 5 by 5 kernel
而应该用一个 5 乘 5 的内核
to look out further.
来进一步研究
But that's a lot more
但是这样的话就要进行
computationally expensive.
更加大量的计算
What you can do instead is use
另外一种方法是使用
dilated convolutions which
扩展卷积这样
allows you to -- which allows
你就可以使用
you to use dilation factors to
扩展因子在卷积
introduce gaps into your
内核里引入间隔
convolution kernel so that
从而可以
you're still using just a 3 by 3
只使用 3 乘 3 的内核
kernel, but you can look out
就能够进行进一步的
further.
研究
And now let's talk about
现在我们来谈谈
subluxal convolution and
亚光圈卷积和
convolution transpose primitive;
卷积转置原语
very commonly used for image
常用于图像
upscaling.
放大
And let's think about how
让我们想一下图象放大
upscaling usually works.
通常是如何进行的
So you have your input data and
现在你有输入数据
you want to upscale it by a
并想用因子 2
factor of 2.
将其放大
So you won't -- you have some
所以你将有一些
missing pixels to compute.
缺失的像素需要计算
And usually upscaling is the
并且通常扩大是
fixed operation with a constant
用恒定过滤器进行的
filter.
固定操作
So for example how would a box
例如 盒式
filter help you to upscale this
过滤器如何帮助你进行图像
image?
扩大
So the box filter, which is take
盒式过滤器获取
the known pixels and copy the
已知像素 并将
known data into the missing
已知的数据复制到缺失的
location to get you upscaled
位置从而获得
results.
扩大的结果
For sub-pixel convolution, your
对于子像素卷积
filters are not constant.
你的过滤器不是常数
Your filters are learned from
过滤器会从数据中
the data.
学习
They are your trained parameters
它们是经过训练的参数
that you get from the training
你可以从训练阶段
step where the system was
获得这些参数 系统接受
trained to do this task; to do
训练从而完成这个任务
image upscaling.
完成图像扩大
So for 2x upscaling you get 4
所以对于 2 倍放大有 4 个
filters.
过滤器
For 4x upscaling you get 16
对于 4 倍放大有 16 个
filters and so on.
过滤器等等
So for our 2x upscaling we get
所以对于 2 倍放大
our 4 filters and we apply them
我们需要用 4 个过滤器
to the input data.
并把它应用在输入数据上
And then the output of that
然后对刚才的操作输出
operation is reshuffled to get
进行重新调整 从而获得
your final full-resolution
最终的全分辨率
image.
图像
And now let's talk about how the
现在让我们来谈谈
convolution transpose primitive
如何使用卷积转置原语
can be used to upscale images.
来放大图像
So we have our inputs and we
我们有输入
still have to compute our
但还需要计算
missing data.
缺失的数据
So the way that this primitive
所以这个原语计算
computes the missing data is
缺失数据的方法是
that it applies a kind of
它使用一种
convolution pass to this
卷积传递给
intermediate result with gaps to
有间隙的中间结果
compute each output pixel.
然后计算每个输出像素
So that's how you get your
这就是如何得到
upscaled output.
放大的结果
And now we're going to show you
现在我们将向你展示
how you can use these new
如何使用这些新的
convolution primitives to
卷积原语在
implement a real-world network.
真实世界的网络中如何操作
So we took this colorization
我们选用了这个着色
network that takes black and
网络 它可以输入黑白
white images as input and
图像 然后输出
produces colorized images.
彩色图像
And this particular network uses
而这个特定的网络能够
the dilated convolution
使用扩张卷积原语
primitive to integrate wider
更快地整合更广泛
global context quicker.
全局环境
And it uses the convolution
并且它使用卷积
transpose primitive to upscale
转置原语来提高
the results of the network.
网络的结果
And now let's look at this
现在我们来看看这个
colorization network in action.
着色网络怎样运行
So in this demo we have a
在这个演示中 我们
collection of black and white
收集了一些黑白
images like this image of a
图像 比如这个
lion.
狮子
And as soon as I tap on this
一旦我点击这个
image, the colorization network
图像 着色网络
will run right here live on the
将在这个设备上
device, and we'll see a
运行 然后我们将看到一个
colorized image.
彩色的图像
And let's try another example
让我们再试试另外一个例子
for this beautiful snowy
这是一座美丽的雪山
mountain.
图像
And now we see it in color.
我们看到现在它是彩色的了
And this beautiful lovely image
还有这个美丽可爱的图像
of a dad and a daughter playing
一位爸爸和女儿在弹
guitar.
吉他
And now you can see them playing
你可以看到现在图像
guitar in color.
是彩色的了
And I really like this one, the
还有这个图像我真的很喜欢
brown bear walking in the
一只棕熊在森林里
forest.
散步
So I think this network does
所以我觉得这个网络
just a really wonderful job.
效果非常不错
Okay. So that's it for the live
好了 这就是现场
demo.
演示
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thank you so much.
谢谢
So we've added all of these new
所以我们添加了所有这些新的
convolution CNN primitives, but
卷积 CNN 原语 但
that's not all.
这并不是全部
We also went back and improved
我们还返回并改进了
the performance of some of the
iOS 10 中可用的
core CNN kernels that were
一些核心 CNN 内核
available to you in iOS 10.
的性能
So this chart will show the
这个图像会显示
performance of the Inception-v3
Inception-v3 网络的
network, which is a commonly
性能 这是一种常用的
used network for image
图像识别
recognition.
网络
So it shows the performance of
它显示了这个网络
this network in iOS 11.
在 iOS 11 中的性能
And as you can see, we're
正如你所看到的 我们
bringing you at least 20 percent
在不同的 iOS 硬件上
performance improvement across
为你带来了至少 20％
different iOS hardware.
的性能提升
And now let's talk about the new
现在我们来谈谈新的
neural network graph API.
神经网络图像 API
the neural networks are commonly
神经网络通常
described using a graph
使用图像抽象化来
abstraction like this
描述 就像这个
visualization of the
Inception-v3 网络的
Inception-v3 network.
可视化一样
And we're now allowing to do
我们现在可以使用
just this using the new graph
新的图像 API 来做到
API.
这一点
So let's zoom in on one of these
所以让我们将这些初始模块中的一个
inception modules.
放大一下
You have filter nodes which
你有过滤节点可以
describe the operations that you
描述对数据
can perform on your data.
执行的操作
Such as convolution, pooling,
比如卷积
etcetera.
池化等
And you have image nodes which
同时你有图像节点
describe how the data flows
可以描述数据如何在
between these different
这些不同操作之间
operations.
流动
So why did we add this new graph
那么我们为什么要添加这个新的图像
API?
API 呢
Well because it's easy to use.
因为它很好使用
You get this compact
你可以获得整个
representation of your entire
网络的紧凑
network and you can save it to
表示 并将其保存到
disk and restore it, and that
磁盘里 还可以将其还原
works across platforms.
它可以在平台间运行
You only need to initialize the
你只需要将图形
graph once and then you can
进行一次初始化 然后就可以
reuse it for multiple input
重新用在多个输入
images.
图像里了
And you can execute the entire
仅仅通过一次调用
graph on the GPU with a single
你就可以在 GPU 上对整个图形
call.
进行操作
There are no intermediate images
没有中间的图像
for you to manage, you just need
需要管理 你只需要
to take care of your input and
做好输入和
output.
输出
Internally we use Metal heaps to
在内部我们使用 Metal 堆
make sure that the memory
来确保所有
footprint of all your
中间图像的
intermediate images is as small
内存占用
as possible.
尽可能小
For example, for the
例如 对于
Inception-v3 network this means
Inception-v3 网络来说
5x memory savings and 10x viewer
这意味着能节省 5 倍的内存空间
allocations, which I think is
和 10 倍的检查器分配
pretty impressive.
我觉得这是相当令人惊叹的
So as I said, the graph does all
正如我所说 图像为你
the groundwork for you.
做了所有的基础工作
It takes care of creating
它会创建
intermediate images.
中间图像
It takes care of sizing them.
并管理图像的大小
It also -- it even sizes your
它甚至会管理
outputs.
输出的大小
It takes care of the padding
它负责处理
policies.
填充策略
It takes care of censoring.
它也会进行审查
So in short, it's a lot less
简而言之 它能让你
code for you to write and a lot
少写很多代码
fewer bugs for you to write as
也就能避免产生很多
well.
错误
And when I say less code, I mean
当我说较少的代码时
a lot less code.
我是说少了非常多的代码
So last year we released this
所以去年我们发布了
Metal recognition sample that
使用 Inception-v3 网络
uses the Inception-v3 network
进行图像识别的 Metal
for image recognition.
识别样本
And we took that sample and
我们把这个样本
converted it to use the new
转换了一下 从而能够使用
graph API and found that we had
新的图像 API 然后发现我们
to write four times less code.
可以少编写四倍的代码
And that's pretty much the same
少写的代码行数与为了
number of lines as Python code
执行相同的网络
you would have to write in the
需要在开源传感器
open-source sensor flow
流程框架中编写的
framework to implement the same
Python 代码行数
network.
一样多
And we just want to mention that
我们只是想提一下
we will be releasing this
我们将发布这个升级的
updated sample code -- updated
示例代码 升级的示例作为
example as sample code.
示例代码
And now having all this
拥有关于你的整个网络的
information about your entire
所有信息 使我们能够
network allows us to deliver the
在不同的视图中
best performance across
提供最佳
different views.
性能
We make it easy for your to
让你可以轻松地在
parallelize between the CPU and
CPU 和 GPU 之间进行
the GPU.
并行处理
so as the graph is executing --
当图像正在执行
as the GPU is executing the
当 GPU 执行一个
graph of one input image, the
输入图像的图形时
CPU can already prepare to
CPU 已经准备好执行
execute the graph for a
不同的输入
different input image.
图像图形了
We can also fuse graph nodes
我们还可以将图形节点
together like the convolution
融合在一起 比如卷积和
and neuron nodes.
神经元节点
And we can execute graph nodes
我们可以同时操作
concurrently.
这些图形节点
So if we look at this inception
所以如果我们再看一下
module again, you can see that
这个初始模块的话
there are multiple rows of these
你就可以看到很多行
nodes that can be executed
节点可以
completely independently of each
完全彼此独立的
other.
操作
And of course the output of
当然 这些独立执行的
these independent executions
输出需要通过
need to be concatenated via
相关节点进行
concatenation nodes.
连接
And the graph is smart enough to
而且这个图像也足够智能
optimize those away as well.
可以将这些进行优化处理
And now let's take a look at how
现在我们来看看如何使用
you can use the new graph API.
新的图形 API
So this is the code for creating
所以这是使用
a convolution node using the
图形 API 创建
graph API.
卷积节点的代码
So it takes an image as source
它需要一个图像作为源
and it also has weights.
而且它也有权重
So let's talk about weights for
所以让我们谈一下
a minute.
权重
Neural networks keep growing
神经网络规模
larger and larger in size.
变得越来越大
And if you have many convolution
如果你的网络中有
nodes in your networks, that
很多卷积节点
means that the overall size of
那就意味着
the weights for your entire
你的整个网络的
network could be quite
总体权重可能
considerable.
相当大
And to help with that we've
为了解决这个问题
added a convolution data source
我们添加了一个
protocol that you can implement
可以执行的卷积数据源协议
and it provides just in time
它能够及时
loading and purging of weights
加载和清除
data.
权重数据
So the idea is that the weights
所以我们的想法是
for your entire network do not
你的整个网络的
have to be loaded in memory all
权重就不用同时
at the same time.
全部加载到内存中
They also do not have to be
它们也不必
loaded in advance.
提前加载
To help minimize the memory
为了帮助将内存空间
footprint, when we initialize
占用降到最小 当我们初始化
the graph and we process a
图形并处理
particular convolution layer,
一个特定的卷积层时
we'll load the weights for that
我们将为这个卷积层
convolution layer and then we
加载权重 然后
purge them before we move on to
将它们清除之后
the next convolution layer.
再进入下一个卷积层
What you have to do is to
你要做的就是使用
implement this initialization
这个初始化方法
method which just knows where
它知道数据的
the data is but it doesn't
位置 但实际上并不会
actually load it.
加载数据
And then when the graph calls
然后当图像调用
the load function that alerts
加载功能的时候
you that the weights need to be
会提醒你需要
loaded.
加载权重
And then when the purge function
然后当图像调用
is called by the graph then you
清除函数功能时
can release the weights.
你可以释放权重
And now let's build a graph.
现在我们来构建一个图像
So here we're implementing this
这里我们正在使用
makeGraph function.
这个 makeGraph 函数
And on the left you can see all
而在左边 你可以看到
the nodes that make up our
构建网络所需的
network that we need to build.
所有节点
So then we create the nodes.
然后我们创建节点
So we create the convolution
创建卷积
node.
节点
The pooling node.
池化节点
And then the rest of the nodes.
和剩下的节点
So we have the nodes.
现在节点有了
How do we connect them into a
那我们如何将节点
graph?
连接成图像呢
So we just take the result image
我们只需把一个节点的
of one node and pass it as a
结果图像作为
source image to the next node.
源图像传递给下一个节点
And then we have our graph.
就形成了图像
And now let's run it on the GPU.
现在让我们在 GPU 上运行这个图表
So first we do our usual Metal
首先像往常一样进行 Metal
setup.
设置
We initialize the graph.
我们初始化这个图像
We take care of our input data
要管理好输入数据
and then we encode the graph to
然后将图像编码到
the GPU.
GPU 上
And the data in the output image
输出图像中的数据
will be -- the output image will
将会在命令缓冲区
be populated with data when the
完成时 将数据填充到
command buffer completes.
输出图像中
And then we have an option to
然后我们可以选择
wait for the GPU to finish.
等待 GPU 完成
But we don't want you to do
但我们并不推荐
that.
这样做
When this happens the CPU is
因为如果这样做的话
waiting for the GPU to finish
CPU 就会等 GPU 完成之后
before it can start encoding the
才能开始对下一轮
next run of the graph.
图像进行编码
And this introduces bubbles into
而这样会将气泡引入你的
your pipeline, which can
传输途径 并对
adversely affect performance.
性能产生不利影响
So what we want you to do
所以我们推荐
instead is to use the new
使用新的
asynchronous executeAsync API.
异步执行的 API
So with this API your Metal
使用这个 API 能让你的 Metal
setup is even smaller.
设置甚至变得更小
So you just need to get the
这样你只需要准备好
Metal device.
Metal 设备
Then you still need to
然后需要
initialize your graph.
初始化图像
Prepare the input data and then
准备好输入数据 然后
you executeAsync call.
执行异步调用
It returns immediately and then
它会立即返回
the output image will be ready
然后当这个代码
when this code inside the
闭包执行时 输出图像
closure executes.
就已经准备好了
But in the meantime, you don't
但在此期间 你不需要
have to wait for the GPU to
等待 GPU 完成
finish, you can already proceed
就可以继续进行
with a coding and new GPU task.
编码和新的 GPU 任务。
And this way the CPU and the GPU
这样 CPU 和 GPU 就
are executing concurrently.
可以同时工作
There are no bubbles in your
并且你的传输途经中
pipeline and they're both
没有气泡 两者都
utilized to full capacity.
被充分地利用了起来
Okay. And now I will do a live
好了 现在我来做一次
demo that demonstrates the
现场演示 演示
performance difference between
同步和异步 API
the synchronous and asynchronous
之间的
APIs.
性能差异
And this demo will be using the
这个演示将使用
Inception-v3 network for image
Inception-v3 网络
recognition.
进行图像识别
All right.
好的
So I will be starting with
我将从同步
synchronous API and here we're
API 开始 在这里我们正在
detecting a water bottle.
检测一个水瓶
And we're getting about 50
平均每个
milliseconds per second per
图像大约有 50
image on average.
毫秒
And now I will switch to the
现在我将切换到
asynchronous API.
异步 API
And now we're getting about 36
现在平均每个图像的
milliseconds per image on
时间约为 36
average.
毫秒
So that's pretty good
所以性能
performance improvement.
有了很大提升
All right.
好的
So that's it for the live demo.
这就是现场演示
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thank you.
谢谢你们
Okay. Now that we've talked
好的 既然我们已经谈过了
about the new neural network
新的神经网络图像
graph API and I showed you how
API 并且向你展示了
easy it is to use and what great
它使用起来多么简单
performance you can achieve with
性能多么强大
it, let's now switch gears and
现在让我们来换个话题
talk about recurrent neural
谈谈循环神经
networks.
网络
So what are recurrent neural
什么是循环神经
networks?
网络呢
So one disadvantage of CNNs is
CNN 的一个缺点是
their inability to remember
无法记住过去
anything that happened in the
发生的
past.
事情
They can take one image as input
它们可以将一个图像
and generate a single output
作为输入 并生成单个输出
such as the set of probabilities
例如图像中所描绘
of what is depicted in the
内容的一组
image.
可能性
RNNs on the other hand have
但 RNN 是有
memory.
记忆的
And they're good at operating on
而且它们擅长按顺序
sequences.
进行操作
So they can take one input such
所以它们可以通过一个输入
as a set of probabilities of
比如图像中所
what is depicted in the image
描绘内容的一组
and generate a sequence of
可能性 然后产生一个
outputs.
输出序列
So a sequence of words that make
一组有逻辑顺序的单词
up a caption for this image.
成为这个图像的标题
They can also take a sequence of
它们还可以通过一个
inputs such as a sentence in
序列输入 比如英语句子
English and generate a sequence
产生多个序列
of outputs such as the same
输出 比如同一个句子翻译成
sentence translated to a
不同的语言
different language like Russian
比如俄语
or Finnish.
或芬兰语
And we support a number of
而且我们还支持许多
different of variants of RNNs.
不同的 RNN 变体
The single gate RNN, the long
单门限 RNN
short-term memory RNN or LSTM,
长短期记忆 RNN 或者说 LSTM
and multiple variants of LSTMs.
以及 LSTM 的多种变体
The GRU and the MGU.
GRU 和 MGU
So let's talk about the simplest
那么让我们来谈谈最简单的
kind of RNN, the single gate
RNN 类型 单门限
RNN.
RNN
the single gate RNN has a
单门限 RNN 具有
recurrent unit which enables the
循环单元 这使得
previous output over RNN to
RNN 之前的输出
affect the output of the
能够影响同一个
subsequent iterations of the
RNN 的后续
same RNN.
迭代输出
But the single gate RNNs are not
但是单门限 RNN 的功能
powerful enough to carry on
还不够强大 不能将
important information for many
重要信息对多次
iterations.
迭代输出构成影响
Because the current output of an
因为单门限 RNN 的
RNN -- of the single gate RNN is
当前输出也是
also its current state.
它的当前状态
There's nothing else there.
没有别的东西
The solution to this is the long
解决这个问题的方法是
short-term memory RNN or LSTM.
长短期记忆 RNN 或简称 LSTM
It's built from single gate RNNs
它由单门限 RNN 构成
and it has an internal memory
并具有内部存储
cell.
单元
And a certain combination of
一个特定的
gates control how the
门限组合可以控制
information flows inside LSTM.
信息在 LSTM 内如何流动
And what is stored and not
并有选择的让信息
stored in the memory cell.
存入存储单元
So let's take a look at the
让我们更详细地
architecture of LSTM in more
看一下 LSTM 的
detail.
架构
As I said, the most important
正如我所说 LSTM 中
entity inside LSTM is the memory
最重要的实体是存储
cell which is updated in every
单元 它在 LSTM 的每个循环期内
duration of LSTM.
都会进行更新
So you can think of each
所以你可以想到
iteration of LSTM is this
LSTM 的每一次迭代
transition between the old and
都是这种新旧
new memory.
内存之间的转换
And now let's talk about the
现在让我们谈谈
gates.
门限
So first there is a forget gate
首先是遗忘门限
which decides what to keep and
它决定旧的内存中
what not to keep from old
哪些能够保留
memory.
哪些不能保留
And then there are the inputs
然后是输入和
and the cell gates and their
单元门限
combined contribution determines
它们的相互组合决定了
what from the current input will
当前输入的什么信息
affect the new memory.
将影响新的内存
And then the combination of all
然后这三个门限
of these three gates is combined
组合在一起来
to update the memory cell.
更新存储单元
And finally, there is the output
最后是输出门限
gate which determines what from
它决定了
the previous inputs the -- the
以前的输入
previous output, the current
输出 当前的
inputs and the new memory will
输入和新的内存中
affect the output of LSTM.
哪些信息将会影响 LSTM 的输出
So now that you know what LSTM
所以现在你知道 LSTM
is made up of, let's take a look
是由什么组成的了 让我们来看看
at how you can create one using
你如何使用我们的框架
our framework.
来创建一个 LSTM
So first you create a descriptor
首先创建一个 LSTM 的
for the LSTM.
描述符
And then you need to initialize
然后你需要将门限
the gates.
初始化
So what controls the gates?
那么门限由什么控制呢
So what controls the gates with
什么能够控制门限
-- what controls how they
控制门限
operate is the trained
如何操作的是经过
parameters.
训练的参数
The ones that come from the
这些参数来自
training step where you train a
为使系统执行一项特定任务
system to do a particular task.
而对其进行训练的步骤
And there are multiple gates for
而且你可以看到
you to initialize as you can
这里有很多门限
see, but we're only showing two
供你进行初始化
initializations just to be
但为了简要说明
brief.
我们只展示两个初始化
And as you can see, we're also
正如你所看到的 我们也
using a data source provider.
在使用一个数据源供应程序
The same one I showed you before
和之前给你看过的一样
to initialize the weights.
它用来初始化权重
And the next step is to create
下一步是创建
our LSTM layer and now we want
我们的 LSTM 层 现在我们
to run it on the GPU.
把它放在 GPU 上运行
So we need to create our arrays
我们需要创建数组
that will hold the input and
保存 LSTM
output for the sequence of the
执行序列的
LSTM executions.
输入和输出
And then we encode the sequence
然后将序列编码到
to the GPU.
GPU 上
And here we're showing you the
在这里 我们向你展示
-- a matrix-based RNN, but we
一种基于矩阵的 RNN 但我们
just want to mention that we
想提一下 我们
also support RNNs that operate
也支持通过卷积在
on MPS images via convolutions.
MPS 图像上操作的 RNN
And now let's take a look at an
现在我们来看一个
actual example.
实际的例子
So we'll use image captioning as
我们将使用图片字幕
an example of using LSTM.
作为使用 LSTM 的例子
So as you recall, I told you
你应该记得 我跟你讲过
that deep learning algorithms
深度学习算法
have two phases.
有两个阶段
The training phase and the
训练阶段和
inference phase.
推理阶段
So to train a system to caption
所以要想训练一个系统
images you need to feed it a
为图像添加说明文字
large number of images with
你需要给它输入大量的带有
human-generated captions.
人为添加说明文字的图像
So what does this system have?
那么这个系统有什么呢
Like what is it made out of?
它是由什么构成的
So this system has a CNN and a
这个系统有一个 CNN 和一个
RNN working together to generate
RNN 一起工作来生成
captions.
说明文字
The CNN is used to figure out
CNN 用于确定
what's depicted in the image and
图像中描述的内容
then the RNN is used to generate
然后经 RNN 生成
the actual caption.
实际的说明文字
And the output of that process
而该过程的输出
is the trained parameters which
是经过训练的参数
are required for the next step,
它们是下一步也就是
the inference step.
推理阶段需要的
So in the inference phase, the
因此 在推理阶段
trained parameters control both
经过训练的参数控制
the operation of the CNN layers
CNN 层
and the operation of the RNN
和 RNN
gates.
门限的运行
And then for each image it's
然后每个图像
processed by both the CNN and
都由 CNN 和 RNN 进行处理
the RNN to generate a caption.
从而生成说明文字
So we already know a good
我们已经知道有一个很好的
network for figuring out what's
网络可以确定
depicted in the image.
图像中描绘的内容
It's the Inception-v3 network,
就是 Inception-v3 网络
so we'll use that.
所以我们将使用它
And we just talked about LSTMs,
而且我们刚刚谈到了 LSTM
so let's use that to generate
所以让我们用它来生成
our caption.
说明文字
And the caption generation phase
说明文字生成阶段
-- the caption generation
说明文字生成过程
process also has two phases.
也分为两个阶段
So first we have the LSTM
首先我们有 LSTM
initialization phase.
初始化阶段
So we run our Inception-v3
然后我们运行 Inception-v3
network and we actually run all
网络 实际上我们运行了所有的
of the layers except the very
层 除了最后一个
last SoftMax layer.
SoftMax 层
And the output of that is a
而输出是一个
feature vector which has
特征向量 它含有
information about what is
关于图像描绘
depicted in the image.
内容的信息
And then we take that feature
然后我们将该
vector and convert it to a
特征向量转换为
compact representation that's
LSTM 所需的
required by LSTM.
紧凑表示
And then run that through LSTM
然后通过 LSTM 运行
to initialize it.
将其初始化
And then once we have our
然后一旦我们有了
initialized LSTM, then we're
初始化的 LSTM 那就
ready for the next phase.
准备好可以进入下一个阶段了
Our actual caption generation
即实际说明文字
phase.
生成阶段
And we start this process by
我们通过向 LSTM 传递
passing in a special sentence
一个特殊的句子开始令牌 ID
start ID token to our LSTM.
来启动这个过程
And the output of that
并且该操作的输出
operations is a sequence of
是一个单词序列
words which are, you know, the
你知道的 就是
words that are connected to what
和图像中所描绘的
is depicted in the image.
内容相关的单词
And then we pass those words to
然后我们将这些单词传递给
a SoftMax layer which computes
一个 SoftMax 层 该层可以计算
probabilities for these words.
这些单词的概率
And we pick the three best ones.
我们选择三个概率最高的
And these three best words are
这三个概率最高的单词也是
also our one-word partial
我们对于特定图像的
captions for a particular image.
说明文字中的单字部分
So we take those words and pass
所以我们将这些单词拿出来
them to the next situation of
并传递给下一个状态的
LSTM which function is to now
LSTM 它的功能是
come up with three best two-word
为图像算出三组
captions for our image and so
最好的双字组合
on.
说明文字
We execute for N iterations
我们执行 N 次迭代
until we reach a stopping
直到达到停止的
condition, which is when we
条件 也就是当
either reach the maximum number
达到我们想要的说明文字
of words that we want to be in
字数上限的时候
our caption, or when the
或者当
probabilities evolving the newly
新生成的说明文字
generating captions drop to 0.
概率下降到 0 的时候
So I know this is still pretty
我知道这仍然
abstract.
很抽象
So let's look at the output of
所以让我们来看看
LSTM -- of an actual output of
LSTM 的输出 也就是
LSTM for several iterations for
LSTM 为了一个特定图像
a particular image.
进行多次迭代之后的实际输出
So in this image we have, you
在这个图像中 你看到
know, our surfer riding a wave.
有冲浪者驾驭在一个波浪上
And we want to compute the top
我们想计算出匹配这张图像的
three captions for this image.
三句最好的说明文字
And in the first iteration of
在 LSTM 的第一次迭代中
LSTM we generate three best
生成了三个最好的
words.
单词
So -- which are our best
所以 这是匹配
one-word captions for this
这张图像的最好的
image.
文字说明
So "man", "a", and "the".
“man”“a”和“the”
And the word "a" has the highest
“a”一词的概率
probability.
最高
So we take these three words and
然后我们把这三个字
we pass them to the next
传递给下一个
iteration of LSTM.
LSTM 的迭代
And in this iteration, for every
在这个迭代中
one of these three starter
对于这三个起始单词中的
words, LSTM generates three new
每一个 LSTM 都生成了三个新词
words that have the highest
它们有和这些
probability of following each
起始单词组合的
one of these starter words.
最高概率
Right? So we have three new
对吧 所以我们有三个
words to follow the word "man".
新词可以和“man”组合
Three new words to follow the
三个新词和“a”
word "a", and three new words to
组合 还有三个新词
follow the word "the".
和“the”组合
And now as you can see, each one
现在你可以看到
of these two-word captions also
每一个双字组合说明
have a probability.
也都有概率
And because the word "a" had
而且由于“a”
such a high probability in the
在第一次迭代中具有
first iteration, then the
如此高的概率 所以
captions that start with the
在第二次迭代中
word "a" in the second iteration
以“a”开头的双字组合
also end up having the highest
最后也具有最高的
probability.
概率
Why? Because the probability of
这是为什么 因为双字
a two-word caption is just a
说明的概率
product of the probabilities of
只是其中两个单词
the words that make up that
概率的
caption.
乘积
So that's how we get these three
这就是我们如何获得这三个的最好
best ones.
方法
And then we take them and we
然后我们留下它们并
move on to the next iteration.
继续下一个迭代
And in the next iteration we
而在下一次迭代中
just add one more word to our
我们只需为已有说明文字
captions so that we have
再添加一个单词
three-word captions.
这样就有了三字说明
And then we compute the
然后我们计算这些
probabilities of those captions
说明文字的概率
and pick the best three.
并挑选三个概率最高的
And we move on to the next
我们继续进行下一次
iteration where we just end up
迭代 只需再添加
adding one more word to our
一个词到
caption.
文字说明中
So we have four-word captions.
然后我们有了四字文字说明
And then we compute the
然后我们计算
probabilities of all these
所有这些文字说明的
captions and pick the best
概率 并挑选概率
three.
最高的三个
And so on -- I think you get the
等等 我觉得你已经
idea.
了解这个方法了
Let's just skip to the end.
那就让我们跳到最后吧
So in the end, we get our three
所以最后 我们得到了三个
top captions for this particular
最好的文字说明来匹配
image.
这个特定的图象
And the best one is a man riding
而其中最好的是一个男人
a wave on top of a surfboard,
踏着冲浪板冲浪
which I think it's pretty close.
我觉得意思已经非常接近了
So -- [applause] and let's now
所以现在我们来
do a demo.
演示一下
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So now we'll do a demo of this
所以现在我们来做一个
-- of the captioning network.
这个字幕网络的演示
So we have a collection of
我们在这里收集了
images here, and as soon as I
一些图像 一旦我点击
tap on an image then the CNN
一张图像 CNN
will run to determine what is
就会运行并确定
depicted in the image.
图像中描绘的内容
And then the RNN will run to
然后 RNN 将运行
generate the actual caption.
并生成实际的说明文字
So let's try it out.
所以让我们试试吧
&gt;&gt; A man riding a wave on top of
&gt;&gt;一个男人踏着
a surfboard.
冲浪板冲浪
&gt;&gt; So we already know this.
&gt;&gt;这个我们已经知道了
Now let's try another image.
现在让我们试试另一张
&gt;&gt; An old truck is parked in the
&gt;&gt;一辆旧卡车停放在
field.
野外
&gt;&gt; So the network actually knows
&gt;&gt;所以网络实际上知道
that it's an old truck and that
这是一辆旧卡车
it's parked and not moving,
它是停放着的 不动的
which I think is pretty
我觉得这非常
impressive.
令人惊叹
Now let's try one more.
再试一次
&gt;&gt; A black and white dog laying
&gt;&gt;一只黑白花纹的狗
in the grass.
躺在草地上
&gt;&gt; So the network knows that
&gt;&gt;所以网络知道
it's a black and white dog and
这是一只黑白色的狗
that it's laying in the grass,
它躺在草地上
not running.
并没有跑
Not walking.
没有走路
Not sitting.
也没有坐着
Laying in the grass.
而是躺在草地上
So pretty cool.
太酷了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thank you.
谢谢
And on this note, let's go to
借着这个说明 我们来
the summary.
总结一下
So in this session we talked
所以在本次会议中
about all of the new primitives
我们讨论了今年在
that we added to the MPS
MPS 框架中
framework this year.
添加的所有新原语。
We've expanded our support for
我们扩大了对
image processing primitives and
图像处理原语和
for convolutional neural
卷积神经网络的
networks.
支持
And we've added support for
我们还增加了对
linear algebra and recurrent
线性代数和循环
neural networks.
神经网络的支持
the framework is optimized for
该框架针对针对
iOS, as I told you, and now
iOS 进行了优化 正如我所说的那样
these primitives are also all
现在这些原语也都在
available on the Mac.
Mac 上可用
We also talked about the new
我们还讨论了新的
neural network graph API and we
神经网络图像 API
showed you how easy it is to
并向你展示了如何
use, to build and execute your
在 GPU 上构建和运行
networks on the GPU.
你的网络
And that it makes it possible
而且 这使我们有可能
for us to deliver the best
在不同的 GPU 上
performance for your networks
为你的网络提供
across the different GPUs.
最佳性能
And we would love to see you use
我们希望大家能够
all of this new functionality to
使用所有这些新功能
create a really great apps and
来创建非常好的应用程序
tell us about it.
并告诉我们
So please check out the related
所以 请查看 Metal 2 相关的
Metal 2 sessions and the
会议和有关
sessions on the core ML and
核心 ML
Accelerate and Vision
Accelerate 和 Vision
Frameworks.
框架的会议
And for more information about
有关此会议的更多信息
this session and for links of
以及示例代码的链接
sample code, please check out
请登陆我们的
this link on our developer
开发者网站查看这个链接
website and thank you so much
非常感谢大家的
for coming, and have a great
出席 祝大家在
WWDC.
WWDC 大会期间有更多收获
[ Applause ]
[掌声]